<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ubuntu on Kovasky Buezo | Software Developer, Cybersecurity Enthusiast</title><link>https://kovasky.me/tags/ubuntu/</link><description>Recent content in Ubuntu on Kovasky Buezo | Software Developer, Cybersecurity Enthusiast</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kovasky.me/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure a Virtual Display for Sunshine using Ubuntu on Xorg with Nvidia</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/ubuntu_virtual_monitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/ubuntu_virtual_monitor/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was tired of playing around with streaming settings that never quite fit my phone&amp;rsquo;s display perfectly. I wanted to maximize the resolution and refresh rate &lt;em&gt;a la &lt;a href="https://github.com/ClassicOldSong/Apollo" target="_blank"&gt;Apollo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which sets up virtual displays automatically for each client but is Windows only. After some trial and error, I figured out how to set up a virtual display under Ubuntu 24.04 (on Xorg) that perfectly matches my phone&amp;rsquo;s screen. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to passthrough an RTX 5000 series GPU to Proxmox</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/rtx_5000_passthrough/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/rtx_5000_passthrough/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently acquired an RTX 5060 GPU and had to look at multiple sources in order to get passthrough working. This will outline all the steps I took in order to get it working on my Dell Poweredge T440 server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="update"&gt;Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of the post edit, Proxmox 9 has been released. I have updated my host to the new version and used
the &lt;a href="https://nvidia.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/5665/~/nvidia-gpu-uefi-firmware-update-tool-for-rtx-5060-series" target="_blank"&gt;update tool for RTX 5060 series🔗&lt;/a&gt; provided by Nvidia. This runs only on Windows so I have passed-through my GPU to a windows VM in order to run the update.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Set up a ramdisk for Plex</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/plex_ramdisk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/plex_ramdisk/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always on the lookout to decrease writes on my consumer SSDs, I stumbled upon the idea of a ramdisk for Plex transcodes. In theory it should offer a performance boost, but in practice I did not really notice any improvements besides lowering SSD writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="editing-fstab"&gt;Editing fstab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to /etc/fstab and open it for edition. You should see your boot disk and any other mapped media there. Add the following line:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>