<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fail2Ban on Kovasky Buezo | Software Developer, Cybersecurity Enthusiast</title><link>https://kovasky.me/tags/fail2ban/</link><description>Recent content in Fail2Ban on Kovasky Buezo | Software Developer, Cybersecurity Enthusiast</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kovasky.me/tags/fail2ban/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Connect Fail2Ban with pfSense</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/pfsense_fail2ban/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/pfsense_fail2ban/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my self-hosted services don&amp;rsquo;t play nicely with Cloudflare proxying. This has led me to use DNS and forgo Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s protection. Many of the guides out there require pfBlockerNG or the use of scripts that authenticate to pfSense via SSH. This guide will help you integrate Fail2Ban with pfSense using only alias lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="serving-the-banlist"&gt;Serving the banlist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need a web server configured to serve a txt file. There are multiple ways you can achieve this but in this case, we&amp;rsquo;ll install an Apache server on a Debian-based Docker host.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using Fail2Ban with Cloudflare on a free account</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/cloudflare_fail2ban/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/cloudflare_fail2ban/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better protect my web accessible services, I decided to use Fail2Ban in conjunction with Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s WAF to block IPs with more than 3 failed login attempts. I already leverage Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s CDN and geo-blocking capabilities on my homelab, so I opted to utilize their WAF to block access to potential attackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the free tier, the WAF is limited to 5 rules, which can easily reach their limit. A workaround is to create a rule that uses a blocklist and then with the Lists API, update it as required.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>