<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Proxmox on Kovasky Buezo | Software Developer, Cybersecurity Enthusiast</title><link>https://kovasky.me/tags/proxmox/</link><description>Recent content in Proxmox on Kovasky Buezo | Software Developer, Cybersecurity Enthusiast</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kovasky.me/tags/proxmox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to passthrough an RTX 5000 series GPU to Proxmox</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/rtx_5000_passthrough/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/rtx_5000_passthrough/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I recently acquired an RTX 5060 GPU and had to look at multiple sources in order to get passthrough working. This will outline all the steps I took in order to get it working on my Dell Poweredge T440 server.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="update">Update&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the time of the post edit, Proxmox 9 has been released. I have updated my host to the new version and used
the &lt;a href="https://nvidia.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/5665/~/nvidia-gpu-uefi-firmware-update-tool-for-rtx-5060-series" target="_blank">update tool for RTX 5060 series🔗&lt;/a> provided by Nvidia. This runs only on Windows so I have passed-through my GPU to a windows VM in order to run the update.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Set up scheduled SMART tests on Proxmox and send alerts via push notifications to your mobile phone</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/proxmox_ntfy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/proxmox_ntfy/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My Synology NAS sends weekly (quick tests) and monthly (extended tests) health reports of its hard drives to my email. I wanted to add this functionality to my Proxmox server to keep an eye on my drives. After some trial and error, I successfully achieved this functionality. Now, I receive these notifications on my phone with the help of ntfy.sh. Here are the steps I took to make it work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enabling SR-IOV for an Intel X540-T2 on Proxmox 8</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/sr_iov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/sr_iov/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the quest to get more performance out of my inter-vm communication, I stumbled upon SR-IOV and virtual functions. I then purchased a 10gbe X540-T2 from a Chinese seller on eBay making sure to get one with a fan, as reports of this specific card say it runs quite hot. After setting everything up, I increased my network performance from 2.5gbps on a vSwitch to 14gbps with virtual function passthrough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iDRAC 9 manual fan control on Dell PowerEdge servers</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/fan_control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/fan_control/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I recently acquired a Dell Poweredge T440, and after installing a GPU the fans skyrocketed. This turned the server into a noise machine. To solve this, I created a script that disables third-party PCI mode and based on a threshold, set the fan speed to 20% or to be controlled by Dell&amp;rsquo;s fan profile. These are the steps I took to make my T440 silent again.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="downgrading-idrac-9-firmware-to-3303030">Downgrading iDRAC 9 firmware to 3.30.30.30&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For this whole setup to work, iDRAC needs to be on firmware 3.30.30.30, as later firmware revisions remove the ability to control the fan speed. The firmware can be downloaded from &lt;a href="https://www.dell.com/support/home/en-us">Dell&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a>. To downgrade, navigate to your iDRAC&amp;rsquo;s web admin page, and under Maintenance-&amp;gt;System Update you can apply the downgrade. After the downgrade, make sure IPMI over LAN is enabled under iDRAC Settings-&amp;gt;Connectivity-&amp;gt;Network-&amp;gt;IPMI Settings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disk passthrough for vms in Proxmox</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/disk_passthrough/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/disk_passthrough/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It has always been recommended to give ZFS full disk control, so after placing my raid card in HBA mode, I went ahead and gave full disk control to my TrueNAS vm.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="figuring-out-the-id-of-the-disk">Figuring out the id of the disk&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Typically, disks are labeled as /dev/sdX, but this can change when adding other drives or moving them around. To circumvent this, it is better to figure out the specific id of the disk to be passed through. To do this, execute the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Starting a VM in Proxmox without Quorum</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/oneshot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/oneshot/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the nodes in my lab runs pfSense and if the vm is down, my network is down. This prevents my nodes from reaching quorum, and thus preventing pfSense from starting. To solve this, I needed a way for the vm to start without quorum. This was achieved by creating a oneshot service that runs at system startup.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="create-the-script">Create the script&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Create a script in a folder of your choice, like &lt;code>/root/startpfSense.sh&lt;/code>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Homelab</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/homelab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/homelab/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is just a post to describe my homelab setup and make it linkable where needed (like in my resume). This is most definitely subject to change at any time as I continue to play with new technologies and keep adding things!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hosts">Hosts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My homelab consists of a one node proxmox host and a terramaster NAS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The specs are:&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="dell-poweredge-t440">Dell Poweredge T440&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2x Xeon Gold 6126 (48 logical cores)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>128GB RAM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1x 118GB Intel Optane NVME&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2x 1TB MX500 SSD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2x 8TB Toshiba SAS Drive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1x 14TB IronWolf Pro Drive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1x Nvidia Quadro M2000&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For storage I have a TerraMaster F2-220 running DSM through tinycore with 2x 6TB Ironwolf HDDs.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>