<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proxmox on Kovasky Buezo</title>
    <link>https://kovasky.me/tags/proxmox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proxmox on Kovasky Buezo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kovasky.me/tags/proxmox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disk passthrough for vms in Proxmox</title>
      <link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/disk_passthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/disk_passthrough/</guid>
      <description>Intro It has always been recommended to give ZFS full disk control, so after placing my raid card in HBA mode, I went ahead and gave full disk control to my TrueNAS vm.
Figuring out the id of the disk Typically, disks are labeled as /dev/sdX, but this can change when adding other drives or moving them around. To circumvent this, it is better to figure out the specific id of the disk to be passed through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a VM in Proxmox without Quorum</title>
      <link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/oneshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/oneshot/</guid>
      <description>Intro One of the nodes in my lab runs PfSense and if the vm is down, my network is down. This prevents my nodes from reaching quorum, and thus preventing PfSense from starting. To solve this, I needed a way for the vm to start without quorum. This was achieved by creating a oneshot service that runs at system startup.
Create the script Create a script in a folder of your choice, like /root/startPfSense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homelab</title>
      <link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/homelab/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is just a post to describe my homelab setup and make it linkable where needed (like in my resume). This is most definitely subject to change at any time as I continue to play with new technologies and keep adding things!
Check out my uptime here.
Hosts My homelab consists of a 2 node proxmox cluster + 1 quorum device. The hosts are a 2010 Mac Pro as well as a M910X Thinkcentre Tiny and the qdevice is a nanopi neo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
