<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Proxmox on Kovasky Buezo | Software Developer, Cybersecurity Enthusiast</title><link>https://kovasky.me/tags/proxmox/</link><description>Recent content in Proxmox on Kovasky Buezo | Software Developer, Cybersecurity Enthusiast</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kovasky.me/tags/proxmox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enabling SR-IOV for an Intel X540-T2 on Proxmox 8</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/sr_iov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/sr_iov/</guid><description>Intro In the quest to get more performance out of my inter-vm communication, I stumbled upon SR-IOV and virtual functions. I then purchased a 10gbe X540-T2 from a Chinese seller on eBay making sure to get one with a fan, as reports of this specific card say it runs quite hot. After setting everything up, I increased my network performance from 2.5gbps on a vSwitch to 14gbps with virtual function passthrough.</description></item><item><title>iDRAC 9 manual fan control on Dell PowerEdge servers</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/fan_control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/fan_control/</guid><description>Intro I recently acquired a Dell Poweredge T440, and after installing a GPU the fans skyrocketed. This turned the server into a noise machine. To solve this, I created a script that disables third-party PCI mode and based on a threshold, set the fan speed to 20% or to be controlled by Dell&amp;rsquo;s fan profile. These are the steps I took to make my T440 silent again.
Downgrading iDRAC 9 firmware to 3.</description></item><item><title>Disk passthrough for vms in Proxmox</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/disk_passthrough/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/disk_passthrough/</guid><description>Intro It has always been recommended to give ZFS full disk control, so after placing my raid card in HBA mode, I went ahead and gave full disk control to my TrueNAS vm.
Figuring out the id of the disk Typically, disks are labeled as /dev/sdX, but this can change when adding other drives or moving them around. To circumvent this, it is better to figure out the specific id of the disk to be passed through.</description></item><item><title>Starting a VM in Proxmox without Quorum</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/oneshot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/oneshot/</guid><description>Intro One of the nodes in my lab runs PfSense and if the vm is down, my network is down. This prevents my nodes from reaching quorum, and thus preventing PfSense from starting. To solve this, I needed a way for the vm to start without quorum. This was achieved by creating a oneshot service that runs at system startup.
Create the script Create a script in a folder of your choice, like /root/startPfSense.</description></item><item><title>Homelab</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/homelab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/homelab/</guid><description>Intro This is just a post to describe my homelab setup and make it linkable where needed (like in my resume). This is most definitely subject to change at any time as I continue to play with new technologies and keep adding things!
Hosts My homelab consists of a one node proxmox host and a terramaster NAS.
The specs are:
Dell Poweredge T440 2x Xeon Gold 6126 (48 logical cores) 128GB RAM 1x 118GB Intel Optane NVME 2x 1TB MX500 SSD 2x 8TB Toshiba SAS Drive 1x 14TB IronWolf Pro Drive 1x Nvidia Quadro M2000 For storage I have a TerraMaster F2-220 running DSM through tinycore with 2x 6TB Ironwolf HDDs.</description></item></channel></rss>