<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proxmox on Kovasky Buezo</title>
    <link>https://kovasky.me/tags/proxmox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proxmox on Kovasky Buezo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kovasky.me/tags/proxmox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disk passthrough for vms in Proxmox</title>
      <link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/disk_passthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/disk_passthrough/</guid>
      <description>Intro While setting up my hosts with FreeIPA, I noticed that home directories were not being created when logging in through ssh. Looking online it seems that most people just use NFS shares to keep home directories the same across devices but I did not want to set up NFS home shares. Fixing this in RHEL-based distros is easy with authconfig but debian-based distros do not come with this. To fix this in debian-based distros is as easy as modiyfing the pam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a VM in Proxmox without Quorum</title>
      <link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/oneshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/oneshot/</guid>
      <description>Intro One of the nodes in my lab runs PfSense and if the vm is down, my network is down. This prevents my nodes from reaching quorum, and thus preventing PfSense from starting. To solve this, I needed a way for the vm to start without quorum. This was achieved by creating a oneshot service that runs at system startup.
Create the script Create a script in a folder of your choice, like /root/startPfSense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homelab</title>
      <link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/homelab/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is just a post to describe my homelab setup and make it linkable where needed (like in my resume). This is most definitely subject to change at any time as I continue to play with new technologies and keep adding things!
Check out my uptime here.
Hosts My homelab consists of a 2 node proxmox cluster + 1 quorum device. The hosts are a 2010 Mac Pro as well as a M910X Thinkcentre Tiny and the qdevice is a nanopi neo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
