<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PfSense on Kovasky Buezo | Software Developer, Cybersecurity Enthusiast</title><link>https://kovasky.me/tags/pfsense/</link><description>Recent content in PfSense on Kovasky Buezo | Software Developer, Cybersecurity Enthusiast</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kovasky.me/tags/pfsense/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure HAProxy with Authelia on pfSense</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/pfsense_haproxy_authelia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/pfsense_haproxy_authelia/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my hosted services do not have OIDC support or any sort of authentication out of the box. Since I am already running an instance of Authelia, I decided to use it to secure those services. It was not as straight forward as I thought, specially using HAProxy on pfSense. There are a few outdated guides that accomplish this but they still missed a step or two to get it working right.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Connect Fail2Ban with pfSense</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/pfsense_fail2ban/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/pfsense_fail2ban/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my self-hosted services don&amp;rsquo;t play nicely with Cloudflare proxying. This has led me to use DNS and forgo Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s protection. Many of the guides out there require pfBlockerNG or the use of scripts that authenticate to pfSense via SSH. This guide will help you integrate Fail2Ban with pfSense using only alias lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="serving-the-banlist"&gt;Serving the banlist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need a web server configured to serve a txt file. There are multiple ways you can achieve this but in this case, we&amp;rsquo;ll install an Apache server on a Debian-based Docker host.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Automatically renew WAN lease on pfSense without rebooting</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/pfsense_wan_update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/pfsense_wan_update/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every now and again I would wake up to my internet being down while my local network being fine. This usually happened when my ISP renewed my assigned IP overnight. The only solution was to reboot my pfSense VM to force the IP lease renewal. Searching the web I discovered it was not uncommon for people to experience this with certain types of modems and virtualized pfSense instances. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I resolved it in my homelab.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Set up multiple domains on one public IP using HAProxy on pfSense</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/haproxy_multi_domain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/haproxy_multi_domain/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently acquired a second domain for one of my projects and wanted to set this up behind the HAProxy instance in my firewall. The problem was that I was already serving my primary domain with it, so I was looking to serve my secondary one as well. It was not as straightforward as I thought but after a bit of Googling and some trial and error, I could proxy multiple domains sharing the same public IP. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did it!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Homelab</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/homelab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/homelab/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a post to describe my homelab setup and make it linkable where needed (like in my resume). This is most definitely subject to change at any time as I continue to play with new technologies and keep adding things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hosts"&gt;Hosts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My homelab consists of a one node proxmox host and a terramaster NAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specs are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="dell-poweredge-t440"&gt;Dell Poweredge T440&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x Xeon Gold 6126 (48 logical cores)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;128GB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x 118GB Intel Optane NVME&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x 1TB MX500 SSD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x 8TB Toshiba SAS Drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x 14TB IronWolf Pro Drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x Nvidia Quadro M2000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For storage I have a TerraMaster F2-220 running DSM through tinycore with 2x 6TB Ironwolf HDDs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Whitelisting in Suricata Package for pfSense</title><link>https://kovasky.me/blogs/whitelist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kovasky.me/blogs/whitelist/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro"&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After tirelessly looking for a solution in order to dynamically create a whitelist for Suricata based on DNS, I decided to create my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="download-the-necessary-files"&gt;Download the necessary files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a whitelist file with all the domains you wish whitelisted. A useful starting point is &lt;a href="https://github.com/anudeepND/whitelist"&gt;anudeepND&amp;rsquo;s collection of commonly white listed domains&lt;/a&gt;. After that, download my &lt;a href="https://github.com/kovasky/homelabscripts/blob/main/pfSense/suricata/generateRules.py"&gt;generateRules.py&lt;/a&gt; script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place these files in a directory of your choice on your pfSense host. For simplicity, I just placed them in /root. Finally, make the script executable by &lt;code&gt;chmod +x ./generateRules.py&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>